<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4C79FBE5ABDE44B083F688A3D6EBDF43" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5807 IH: Empowering Individuals to Succeed Through Education and Workforce Training Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5807</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251021">October 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act to establish a fund to provide support services for individuals participating in certain training activities under such Act.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3488C20BFE624F5C85BBB935EF654C9A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8111882007AB40DB966302DDF1833B50" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Empowering Individuals to Succeed Through Education and Workforce Training Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H236CD9F31CD7405587118B8F27554ED9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Support services training fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subtitle D of title I of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3221">29 U.S.C. 3221 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H86B1E1D5C45C4B41BB2DA154B6041E8D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating section 172 as section 173; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBEA194216AD44C24BC0ECF1E1CE590B2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding after section 171 the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HDEB8477C7B674B4794773C1A0E3EF899" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC055E5C770DA4D7184420055DA43ABE3"><enum>172.</enum><header>Support services training fund</header> 
<subsection id="HCD9F8F8978D945118779B3FF52A26B16"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of specified support services training fund</header><text>From the amounts appropriated to carry out this section, the Secretary shall award competitive grants to qualified applicants to provide specified support services for individuals participating in training activities covered under section 134(c)(3) of title I and section 231 of title II of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H6B5D8358A8F94FB6A41AC15742D3E235"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Qualified applicant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <quote>qualified applicant</quote> means a local board, a consortium of local boards, or a State board acting on behalf of or in partnership with a consortium of local boards.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H90412F9A22BF49F2BED7F2EFBFB3A249"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To receive a grant under subsection (a), a qualified applicant shall submit to the Secretary an application in such manner, at such time, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including a description of how such qualified applicant plans to partner with other organizations, including the State agency responsible for administering the State program for temporary assistance for needy families (TANF) funded under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act and the supplemental nutrition assistance program under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2012">7 U.S.C. 2012 et seq.</external-xref>), to provide specified support services.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HCDF28FE09244499FA8788115A84092B8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds</header> <paragraph id="H8748DFC47A144BE49A69C01E80BB7765"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible participant</header><text>Individuals participating in training services covered under section 134(c)(3) of title I or section 231 of title II of this Act are eligible to receive specified support services provided under this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H32D256F212C841409DD0431DF6F76219"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Specified support services</header><text>The qualified support services to be provided by a grantee under this section include—</text> <subparagraph id="H05DDFCA2CACD4C00A9C218A833D9010F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>supportive services described in section 3(59), and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H52A129DB9BD64D459D5E19DACD4DF427"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such other services or funding not described in such section as a grantee identifies as important for an individual to successfully complete training services covered under this section, including funding for, or the provision of, groceries and after-hours childcare.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9594DCCAEBA942AA852156D2421AE0C9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Individual grant amounts</header><text>The amount of an individual grant awarded under this section shall not exceed more than $2,000,000 per year.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

